A Guide to the Charles Olson Research Collection 1969.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series I: Works, undated, 1927-1969
  - A. Maximus Poems
    - The Vault of Heaven, from which the rains spring... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 8p. Manuscript written on back of letter dated February 23, 1963, from Ronald Johnson to CO. (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Turn out your ever-loving arms... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 3p. (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - "At the boundary of the mighty world." Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 22p. (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Maximus, From Dogtown -- IV. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy/Proofs/Galley Proofs. 64p. (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - I looked up and saw its form through everything... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - One of the Bronze Plaques Which Decorate These Shores... Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 3p. (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - A Letter, on FISHING GROUNDS OF by Walter H. Rich. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 6p. (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Maximus, to Gloucester, Letter 157. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 13p. (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Why light, and flowers?... Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 9p., May 23, 1963. (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - You drew the space in reticule... Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Civic Disaster. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 7p. (Box 4, Folder 175)
    - June 6th, 1963. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 8p., June 6, 1963. (Box 4, Folder 176)
    - Into the hill... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 3p. (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - The distances up and down... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 7p., August 8, 1966. (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - Tantrist sat saw on the Lingam... Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 3p. (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - I stand up on you, Fort Place. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p. (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - Rotundum... Manuscript/Photocopy. 4p. (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - Or Lindsay roared upon the town firing barges... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Photostat. 21p. (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - 13 vessels... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 15p. Manuscript written on letter, dated May 29, 1963, from Jeremy Prynne to CO., June 1963. (Box 4, Folder 183)
    - The lap of one of the two women... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p. Manuscript written on envelope, date June 12, 1963, from Totem Press to CO. (Box 4, Folder 184)
    - A Contract Entered Into By the Aforesaid Ship... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 12p. (Box 4, Folder 185)
    - The River Map and we're done. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 8p., June 15, 1963. (Box 4, Folder 186)
    - I set out now in a box upon the sea. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 3p. (Box 4, Folder 187)
    - Having descried the nation... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p. (Box 4, Folder 188)
    - Said Mrs. Tarantino... Manuscript/Typescript. 6p. (Box 4, Folder 189)
    - Bona Dea... Manuscript/Proof. Manuscript written on envelope, dated March 23, 1963, from Ken Irby to CO. (Box 4, Folder 190)
    - The last man... Empty. (Box 4, Folder 191)
    - I believe in God... Empty. (Box 4, Folder 192)
    - I told the woman... Empty. (Box 4, Folder 193)
    - Main Street is deserted... Manuscript. 6p. (Box 4, Folder 194)
    - Imbued with the light of heaven... Manuscript. 23p. (Box 4, Folder 195)
    - I looked up and saw... Empty. (Box 4, Folder 196)
    - The shape of Weymouth... Manuscript/typescript. 2p. Manuscript written on back of envelope, dated June 28, 1963, from the John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation to CO., June 29, 1963. (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - It says the Amitie sailed for New England with etc... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p. (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - The Return to the Mail-Bag... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p. (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - Followed his sow to apples... Manuscript. 1p. (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - The authority of Cape Ann... Manuscript. 1p. Manuscript written on a copy of excerpts from three letters, one dated March 9, 1963, from Ed Dorn to "Ken", the second undated from Robert Kelly, and the third dated October 27, 1963, from Ron Loewinsohn to "Fred." (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Ships for the West Indies... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p. (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - Watch-house Point... Empty. (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - West Gloucester. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p. (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - Williams Stevens, first to venture... Manuscript. 5p. (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - Stevens song. Typescript. 1p. Manuscript notebook separated to "Notebooks." (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - The Bulgar... Manuscript. 2p. (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - Astride the Cabot fault... Manuscript/Typescript. 12p. (Box 4, Folder 208)
    - Rages strain Dog of Tartarus... Manuscript/Typescript. 15p., February 12, n.y. (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - 7 years and you cld carry cinders in yr hand... Typescript. 1p. (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - Wonis kvam... Typescript. 1p. (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - The Condition of the Light from the Sun. Manuscript. 1p. Written on back of State of New York Employee's Statement of Salary and Deductions, dated December 11, 1963. (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - Signature to Petition. Manuscript. 2p. Broadsheet copy of poem separated to oversized materials. (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - Space and Time the saliva... Empty. (Box 4, Folder 214)
    - The Alligator... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p. (Box 4, Folder 215)
    - Sun upside down... Manuscript. 14p. (Box 4, Folder 216)
    - "Home", to the shore... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., March 14, 1964. (Box 4, Folder 217)
    - Her Headland... Typescript. 1p. (Box 4, Folder 218)
    - To have the bright body of sex and love... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., March 28, n.y. (Box 4, Folder 219)
    - Maximus to himself June 1964. Manuscript. 1p. (Box 4, Folder 220)
    - Publish my own soul... Typescript. 1p., August 1, 1964. (Box 5, Folder 221)
    - I believe in religion not magic or science... Typescript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 222)
    - Fire it back into the continent... Typescript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 223)
    - The sky of Gloucester... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p. Manuscript written on photocopies of poems by Victor Coleman, Gerrit Lansing, Diane Di Prima, William Dorn and Kidder Smith., August 6, n.y. (Box 5, Folder 224)
    - The-Man-With-The-House-On-His-Head... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., August 8, 1964. (Box 5, Folder 225)
    - The Feathered Bird of the Harbor of Gloucester. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., August 8, 1964. (Box 5, Folder 226)
    - Coiled, throughout the system... Typescript. 1p., August 8, 1964. (Box 5, Folder 227)
    - Right at the Cut... Typescript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 228)
    - The Wolf slinks off... Manuscript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 229)
    - There was a salt-works at Stage Fort. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., August 19, 1964. (Box 5, Folder 230)
    - The NEW Empire. Typescript. 1p., August 20, n.y. (Box 5, Folder 231)
    - The Cormorant and the Spindle... Manuscript/Typescript. 5p. Manuscript written on back of shipping envelope, undated, from Peter Smith to CO. (Box 5, Folder 232)
    - Cole's Island. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 17p., September 9, 1964. (Box 5, Folder 233)
    - My shore, my sounds, my earth... Manuscript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 234)
    - Hector-body... Manuscript/Typescript. 1p. and 1 notebook., January 20, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 235)
    - Sweet Salmon... Photocopy. 1p., March 15, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 236)
    - Poem 143. The Festival Aspect. Manuscript/Typescript. 8p., March 29, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 237)
    - George Decker... Photocopy. 2p. (Box 5, Folder 238)
    - Ramp: to eat God's food raw. Typescript. 1p., April 1, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 239)
    - He came accompanied by the night... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p. Manuscript written on enveloped, dated March 15, 1965, from the Socratic Literary Society to CO., ca. March 30, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 240)
    - "Each Night is No Loss..." Manuscript. 5p., ca. July 28, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 241)
    - Maximus, in Gloucester Sunday, LXV. Manuscript/Typescript. 4p., August 22, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 242)
    - "O Quadriga..." Manuscript/Photocopy. 5p. Manuscript written on back of letter, dated August 3, from Michel Beaujois to CO., ca. August 3, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 243)
    - Fierce work it were to do again. Photocopy. 1p., ca. August-September 1965. (Box 5, Folder 244)
    - The Savages, or Voyages of Samuel de Champlain of Brouage. Typescript. 3p. Manuscript note on back of last page. (Box 5, Folder 245)
    - Physically, I am home... Manuscript. 7p., September 29, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 246)
    - North in the ice... Manuscript. 2p., September 29, n.y. (Box 5, Folder 247)
    - Lost from the loss of her dragger... Manuscript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 248)
    - The Ocean. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p. and 1 notebook. Typescript note from CO to "Harv" at bottom of page 2., September 30, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 249)
    - Dogtown - Ann, Robinson Davis... Typescript. 3p. Typescript note from CO to "Robert" on top of page 1. (Box 5, Folder 250)
    - To make those silent vessels go... Manuscript. 4p. (Box 5, Folder 251)
    - Cornely... Manuscript. 4p. (Box 5, Folder 252)
    - "Cromlech" of course it is... Manuscript. 6p. (Box 5, Folder 253)
    - Echidna is the bite of the asp... Empty. (Box 5, Folder 254)
    - "Cut Creek," the River is... Manuscript. 2p. (Box 5, Folder 255)
    - Maximus of Gloucester. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p. Manuscript written on card, "SMILE: Deaf Mute Educational System.", November 5, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 256)
    - The Death of Carl Olsen. Manuscript. 6p., November 5, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 257)
    - Tall in the Fort... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., November 18, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 258)
    - Here in the Fort my heart doth harden... Manuscript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 259)
    - Migration in fact... Photocopy. 1p., November 20, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 260)
    - The winter the Gen. Starks was stuck. Manuscript/Typescript. 5p., December 21, 1965. (Box 5, Folder 261)
    - December 22nd. Manuscript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 262)
    - The whole thing has run so fast away... Typescript. 1p. Typescript note from CO to "Dearest Kate" at top of page., January 9, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 263)
    - Like mountains... Manuscript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 264)
    - Sunday, January 16, 1966. Manuscript/Typescript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 265)
    - These People sat right out my window too. Photocopy. 1p., January 18, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 266)
    - On the Earth's Edge... Photocopy. 2p., January 18, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 267)
    - Snow At Evening. Manuscript. 1p. Written on envelope, postmarked January 17 n.y., from Artist's Workshop Press to CO., January 20, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 268)
    - If the Deaths Do Not Stop We'll Have No Earth or Years Left. Typescript. 1p., January 21, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 269)
    - February 3, 1966 High Tide 10.6 Feet 8:43 AM. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p. (Box 5, Folder 270)
    - The Land as Haithubu. Photocopy. 1p., ca. February 4, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 271)
    - A 3rd morning it's beautiful... Manuscript. 12p., February 7, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 272)
    - I have been an ability - a machine... Manuscript. 12p. (Box 5, Folder 273)
    - That island floating in the sea... Manuscript. 1p., June 17, 1962. (Box 5, Folder 274)
    - The Mountain of no difference... Manuscript. 1 notebook. (Box 5, Folder 275)
    - Bottled up for days... Manuscript. 3p. (Box 5, Folder 276)
    - Got me home, the light snow gives the air, falling. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., February 16, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 277)
    - Same thought - 2. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., February 16, n.y. (Box 5, Folder 278)
    - The living hand... Manuscript. 1p. (Box 5, Folder 279)
    - The Day's Beginnings. Manuscript. 2p., March 7, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 280)
    - Valorem is rate... Manuscript. 1p. (Box 6, Folder 281)
    - As of Parsonses or Fishermans Field or Cressy Beach... Manuscript. 5p., March 29, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 282)
    - White ships all covered with ice... Manuscript. 1p. (Box 6, Folder 283)
    - The northwest course of shifting man... Manuscript. 1p., April 3, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 284)
    - The moon is the measure... Photocopy. 1p. (Box 6, Folder 285)
    - The Groaner shakes louder... Manuscript. 1p., April 1966. (Box 6, Folder 286)
    - Land's End - Times End and then. Manuscript. 3p. Manuscript written on envelope, postmarked April 8, 1966, from Timothy Leary Defense Fund to CO., April 11, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 287)
    - Light signals and mass points. Manuscript. 2p. (Box 6, Folder 288)
    - Having developed the differences... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p. and 1 notebook., April 25, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 289)
    - Just as Morning Twilight and the Gulls, The Full Flower Moon, Gloucester, May 1966. Manuscript. 3p., May 3, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 290)
    - Essay on Queen Tiy. Manuscript. 1 notebook. (Box 6, Folder 291)
    - The usefulness of tramping out with great care... Manuscript/Typescript. 9p. and 1 notebook. (Box 6, Folder 292)
    - Oceania, the Child of the Moment of the Maid and Thought. Manuscript. 1 notebook. Manuscript written on CO's checkbook and blank checks. (Box 6, Folder 293)
    - Mareoceanum. Manuscript. 1p. (Box 6, Folder 294)
    - To my Portuguese... Manuscript. 5p., June 15, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 295)
    - Same day, Later. Manuscript. 1p. (Box 6, Folder 296)
    - When do poppies bloom... Manuscript. 2p., June 15, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 297)
    - An Art Called Gothonic. Manuscript/Typescript. 4p. and 1 notebook., June 14, n.y. (Box 6, Folder 298)
    - Night June 19th with some hope my own daughter... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p. (Box 6, Folder 299)
    - This town works at dawn... Manuscript. 1p. Written on envelope, postmarked June 17, 1966, from Harcourt, Brace and World, Inc. to CO., June 20, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 300)
    - The hour of the evening... Photocopy. 7p., July 12, 1966. (Box 6, Folder 301)
    - The history of Earth... Manuscript. 1p. Written on letter, dated July 14, 1966, from "Robert" to CO. (Box 6, Folder 302)
    - Migration in fact... Manuscript. 2p., August 8, n.y. (Box 6, Folder 303)
    - The boats' lights in the dawn... Photocopy. 3p. (Box 6, Folder 304)
    - Out of the light of Heaven... Manuscript. 9p., February 7, 1967. (Box 6, Folder 305)
    - Hotel Steinplatz, Berlin, December 25 (1966). Manuscript/Typescript. 5p. Manuscript written on letter, dated November 30, 1966, from C. Richard Clark to CO. (Box 6, Folder 306)
    - 11 o'clock at night... Manuscript. 1p. (Box 6, Folder 307)
    - Celestial evening, October 1967. Manuscript. 4p. (Box 6, Folder 308)
    - (Literary Result). Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., October 18, 1967. (Box 6, Folder 309)
    - The Telesphere. Manuscript. 2p., November 15, 1967. (Box 6, Folder 310)
    - Sun right in my eyes... Manuscript. 1p. Written on envelope., December 2, 1967. (Box 6, Folder 311)
    - Great Washing Rock... Manuscript. 2p., December 24, 1967. (Box 6, Folder 312)
    - The sea's boiling... Manuscript. 1 leather-bound "Week-At-A-Glance" notebook., ca. December 1967. (Box 6, Folder 313)
    - The salmon of wisdom... Manuscript. 1p., January 29, 1968. (Box 6, Folder 314)
    - That's the combination... Empty. (Box 6, Folder 315)
    - That there was a woman in Gloucester... Manuscript. 2p., February 18, 1968. (Box 6, Folder 316)
    - Added to making a Republic... Manuscript. 6p. Written on letter and envelope, dated February 1, 1968, from Joyce Benson to CO., March 6, 1968. (Box 6, Folder 317)
    - Wholly absorbed... Manuscript/Photocopy. 2p., March 1968. (Box 6, Folder 318)
    - Take the earth in under a single review... Manuscript. 1p. and 1 book. Manuscript written on "The Blue Stairs (poems) by Barbara Guest, New York: Corinth Books, 1968. Manuscript also written on typescript note, dated March 23-24, from unknown to "my dear Charles". (Box 6, Folder 319)
    - That great descending light of day... Manuscript. 1p., July 21, n.y. (Box 6, Folder 320)
    - And melancholy. Manuscript. 1p., July 23, 1968. (Box 7, Folder 321)
    - Outer Darkness Inner Schoodic... Manuscript. 2p. (Box 7, Folder 322)
    - Above the head of John Day's pasture land... Manuscript/Carbon copy. 24p., June 30, 1968. (Box 7, Folder 323)
    - I'm going to hate to leave this Earthly Paradise. Manuscript/Typescript/Proof. 30p., August 5, 1968. (Box 7, Folder 324)
    - December 18th. Manuscript/Typescript. 6p., December 18, 1968. (Box 7, Folder 325)
    - Flower of the underworld. Manuscript. 1p. (Box 7, Folder 326)
    - Between Cruiser and Plato... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p. Manuscript written on back of postcard, dated December 27, 1968, from Radcliffe College to CO., January 1, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 327)
    - Full moon [staring out window... Manuscript. 1p., March 4, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 328)
    - The first of morning... Manuscript. 1 notebook., April 20, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 329)
    - The left hand is the calyx of the Flower... Manuscript. 1p. Written on the back cover of "A Curriculum for the Study of the Soul: Pleistocene Man" by Charles Olson, Institute of Further Studies, 1968., April 20, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 330)
    - The Island, the River, the shore... Manuscript. 1p., May 24, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 331)
    - Just to have her body in my mind... Manuscript. 1p., June 18, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 332)
    - Enyalion of brown earth... Manuscript. 1 notebook., June 22, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 333)
    - Slowness which are an amount... Manuscript. 2p. Written on letter, dated June 20, from "Al" to CO., June 23, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 334)
    - I was bold, I had courage... Manuscript. 40p., June 26, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 335)
    - Golden Venetian Light From Back of Agamenticus Height Falling Like Zeus' dust All Over the River and marsh as Night Falling. Manuscript/Typescript. 5p. Manuscript written on envelope, postmarked June 12, 1969, from D. Hise to CO., June 28, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 336)
    - Short Possible Poem to Follow... Manuscript. 1 notebook., June 29, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 337)
    - His health, his poetry, and his love... Manuscript. 1 notebook., July 16, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 338)
    - Thank God I chose a Protestant Federalist town. Typescript. 4p., July 16, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 339)
    - The unit the smallest there is. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., July 16, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 340)
    - Father Sky Mother Earth. Manuscript. 7p. and 1 notebook. Manuscript written on some materials from "The Marquis Biographical Library Society.", July 15, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 341)
    - Mother of the tides... Manuscript. 2p., July 28, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 342)
    - Melkarth of Tyre... Photocopy. 1p., September 11, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 343)
    - Nasturtium is still my flower... Empty. (Box 7, Folder 344)
    - I live underneath the light of day... Empty. (Box 7, Folder 345)
    - The Blow is Creation... Manuscript. 39p., November 26, 1969. (Box 7, Folder 346)
    - My wife my car my color myself. Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1969. (Box 7, Folder 347)
    - Early Proofs and Notes (1/3). Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 26p. (Box 8, Folder 348)
    - Early Proofs and Notes (2/3). Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 25p. (Box 8, Folder 349)
    - Early Proofs and Notes (3/3). Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 28p. (Box 8, Folder 350)
    - Notes to publisher regarding proofs. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 41p. (Box 8, Folder 351)
    - Maximus Poems IV, V, VI: Front matter. Photocopied proof. 3p. (Box 9, Folder 352)
    - Maximus Poems Book IV (p. 1-71). Photocopied proof. 75p. (Box 9, Folder 353)
    - Maximus Poems Book V (p. 72-108). Photocopied proof. 38p. (Box 9, Folder 354)
    - Maximus Poems Book VI (p. 109-171). Photocopied proof. 65p. (Box 9, Folder 355)
    - Maximus Poems IV, V, VI: Four Point Section (p. 172-191). Photocopied Proof. 22p. (Box 9, Folder 356)
    - Maximus Poems: Book IV (p. 1-71). Photocopied proof. 74p. Copy 2. (Box 10, Folder 357)
    - Maximus Poems: Book V (p. 72-108). Photocopied proof. 39p. Copy 2. (Box 10, Folder 358)
    - Maximus Poems: Book VI (p. 109-171). Photocopied proof. 64p. Copy 2. (Box 10, Folder 359)
    - Maximus Poems IV, V, VI: Four Point Section (p. 172-191). Photocopied proof. 21p. Copy 2. (Box 10, Folder 360)
    - Maximus Poems IV, V, VI: galley proofs (1/4). Photocopy. 33p. (Box 11, Folder 361)
    - Maximus Poems IV, V, VI: galley proofs (2/4). Photocopy. 32p. (Box 11, Folder 362)
    - Maximus Poems IV, V, VI: galley proofs (3/4). Photocopy. 26p. (Box 11, Folder 363)
    - Maximus Poems IV, V, VI: galley proofs (4/4). Photocopy. 29p. (Box 11, Folder 364)
    - Maximus Poems IV, V, VI: cover, front matter printer proof. Photocopy. 2p. (Box 11, Folder 365)
    - Maximus Poems IV, V, VI: dedication page proof. Original print. 1p. (Box 11, Folder 366)
    - Maximus, From Dogtown: printer proofs and notes. Manuscript/Print/Photocopy. 14p. (Box 11, Folder 367)
    - Maximus IV, V, VI: annotated poems. Manuscript/Typescript. 12p. (Box 12, Folder 368)
    - Maximus IV, V, VI: notes and poems. Manuscript/Typescript. 24p. (Box 12, Folder 369)
    - Maximus IV, V, VI: notes. Manuscript. 17p. (Box 12, Folder 370)
    - Maximus IV, V, VI: rejected poems. Manuscript/Typescript. 9p. (Box 12, Folder 371)
  - B. The Distances
    - The Distances. Galley Proof. p. 1-19, Front Matter., ca. February 1961. (Box 13, Folder 372)
    - The Distances. Galley Proof. p. 20-39., ca. February 1961. (Box 13, Folder 373)
    - The Distances. Galley Proof. p. 40-60., ca. February 1961. (Box 13, Folder 374)
    - The Distances. Galley Proof. p. 61-76., ca. February 1961. (Box 13, Folder 375)
    - The Distances. Galley Proof. p. 77-93., ca. February 1961. (Box 13, Folder 376)
    - The Distances. Galley Proof. p. 94-96., ca. February 1961. (Box 13, Folder 377)
  - C. Collected Poems
    - ABCs. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 2p., ca. 1948. (Box 14, Folder 378)
    - ABCs (2). Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 2p., April 10, 1950. (Box 14, Folder 379)
    - ABCs (3: for Rimbaud). Manuscript/Typescript. 1p., June 1950. (Box 14, Folder 380)
    - abt the dead he sd... Typescript/Photocopy. 2p., 1960. (Box 14, Folder 381)
    - Across Space and Time. Manuscript/Typescript. 1p., ca. April - November 5, 1960. (Box 14, Folder 382)
    - Absolutely vernal. Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1965. (Box 14, Folder 383)
    - Abstract No. 1, Yucatan. Typescript. 1p., ca. March 5, 1951. (Box 14, Folder 384)
    - Adamo Me... Manuscript/Typescript. 5p., June 1950. (Box 14, Folder 385)
    - Adamo Me... Manuscript/Typescript. 4p. See letter, dated June 30, 1950, from Robert Creeley to Francis Boldereff., June 1950. (Box 14, Folder 386)
    - Afica. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 5p., ca. August 21-25, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 387)
    - Afternoon. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1945 - October 1946. (Box 14, Folder 388)
    - The Alba. Manuscript. 1p., January 13, 1956. (Box 14, Folder 389)
    - All Havens Astern. Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1958-1962. (Box 14, Folder 390)
    - All pink from the bath... Manuscript. 1p., ca. November 27, 1959. (Box 14, Folder 391)
    - All things stand out against the sky... Typescript. 1p., ca. December 1949 - March 1950. (Box 14, Folder 392)
    - All You Can Do. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1948-1950. (Box 14, Folder 393)
    - The Allegory of Wealth. Manuscript/Typescript. 4p., June 13, 1961. (Box 14, Folder 394)
    - The Americans. Manuscript. 1p., December 17, 1961. (Box 14, Folder 395)
    - The Americans. Typescript. 2p., ca. December 1961. (Box 14, Folder 396)
    - Anniversary. Manuscript/Typescript. 5p., ca. September 1957 - May 1962. (Box 14, Folder 397)
    - Anubis will stare. Be sure... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 14p. Poem written as part of letter from Charles Olson to Constance Olson., March 30, 1956. (Box 14, Folder 398)